<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>TIPEAS</title>
    <link href="http://tipeas.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://tipeas.com" />
    <updated>2024-07-12T11:28:46+07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Tipeas</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://tipeas.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>AstraZeneca&#x27;s Vaccine Scandal: EMA&#x27;s Controversial Stance Amidst Blood Clot Concerns</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tipeas</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://tipeas.com/astrazenecaand039s-vaccine-scandal-emaand039s-controversial-stance-amidst-blood-clot-concerns.html"/>
        <id>http://tipeas.com/astrazenecaand039s-vaccine-scandal-emaand039s-controversial-stance-amidst-blood-clot-concerns.html</id>
        <media:content url="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/astrazeneca1-2.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Vaccine"/>
            <category term="UK"/>
            <category term="Health"/>
            <category term="EU"/>
            <category term="EMA"/>
            <category term="Covid-19"/>
            <category term="Corrupt"/>
            <category term="Bribe"/>
            <category term="AstraZeneca"/>

        <updated>2024-04-30T09:16:00+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/astrazeneca1-2.jpg" alt="" />
                    The admission by AstraZeneca that their COVID-19 vaccine can cause rare but severe blood clotting disorders has sent shockwaves through the medical community and raised serious questions about the safety of the vaccine. However, the European Medicines Agency (EMA) has taken a controversial stance amidst&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/astrazeneca1-2.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>The admission by AstraZeneca that their COVID-19 vaccine can cause rare but severe blood clotting disorders has sent shockwaves through the medical community and raised serious questions about the safety of the vaccine. However, the European Medicines Agency (EMA) has taken a controversial stance amidst this scandal, which has further fueled public outrage and suspicion.</p>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhIVIXnjg-Y08m_HoBVmkR_WpyEVB76502FbpWmdx6DX3z-7l33cRkNF7JSG9jsx0wq-ugzfTqnZHde6zara3CBcPJl6EjXXIltYPFEYm7AiDm73vAUoq3QSNcmoubwXbdC1tVYWeoWjHMSzUhEgrN-8PjuKnVyF1GZq-DjclgroMrgJJj2sphzSVPYmGE/s512/astrazeneca1.jpg" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/astrazeneca1.jpg" width="320" height="180" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/astrazeneca1-xs.jpg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/astrazeneca1-sm.jpg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/astrazeneca1-md.jpg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/astrazeneca1-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/astrazeneca1-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/astrazeneca1-2xl.jpg 1600w"></a></div>
<p> </p>
<p>Despite being aware of reports of blood clot complications associated with the AstraZeneca vaccine, the EMA has stated that "no link between the vaccine and blood clot complications was found" and continues to recommend the vaccine, arguing that "the benefits outweigh the risks." This statement has been met with fierce criticism, as many see it as a deceptive attempt to downplay the potential dangers of the vaccine.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Critics argue that the EMA's position is essentially saying, "we don't know if it's relevant or not, you can just use it." This ambiguous stance does little to reassure the public and has only heightened concerns about the vaccine's safety. Instead, what is needed is a clear and definitive statement from the EMA, backed by established evidence, that the AstraZeneca vaccine does not cause deadly blood clots.</p>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhpZ3XpYlZDqLyWcnsv5RbFLzGrgpH3eeZ7oMx_lNRtR7E88dXdFH8NIUB_IBgaR-4DTWJOr2s5I2VFLBemrcgZxmEjaCvZcSSkcg1qG-p6GJ7oSWVVcfbu4bzeUqdt2Hsu7zThMcTqx07jhWdEk3m7RBfF5mr-JL151AZAaZ-Rx8RnmefUC6Pz7_cAjRY/s649/ema_554886b2519ac.jpg" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/ema_554886b2519ac.jpg" width="320" height="203" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/ema_554886b2519ac-xs.jpg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/ema_554886b2519ac-sm.jpg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/ema_554886b2519ac-md.jpg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/ema_554886b2519ac-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/ema_554886b2519ac-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/ema_554886b2519ac-2xl.jpg 1600w"></a></div>
<p> </p>
<p>The most suspicious aspect of the EMA's handling of this scandal is that, while they could have recommended that Europe order safer vaccines such as Moderna and Pfizer, their statements appear to have encouraged further orders for the 200 million doses that Europe had already committed to purchasing from AstraZeneca. This raises serious questions about the EMA's priorities and whether they are truly acting in the best interests of public health.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The EMA's controversial stance has only added fuel to the fire of public outrage surrounding the AstraZeneca vaccine scandal. Many are now questioning the independence and integrity of the agency, accusing them of being too closely aligned with the interests of pharmaceutical companies. The lack of transparency and clear communication from the EMA has further eroded public trust in the vaccine approval process and the institutions meant to protect public health.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Moreover, there needs to be a thorough and independent investigation into the EMA's handling of this scandal, to determine whether there were any conflicts of interest or undue influence from the pharmaceutical industry. The public deserves answers and accountability from those entrusted with safeguarding their health.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The AstraZeneca vaccine scandal has exposed not only the potential dangers of rushed vaccine development but also the flaws and weaknesses in our regulatory system. The EMA's controversial stance has only deepened the crisis of confidence in the vaccine approval process and highlighted the need for greater transparency, independence, and public accountability.</p>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi65s8dqIf5P4Q20XmTHJ1kgusahZkQxJRdBMDbZJ27r2f2SmpTxf1rLEqpPtNHpKVG26EA5EctzppwcbUU0kLE8aixg-k8GVjL4RldUmu7YKUL9JyyUpFchK1HVwaGbtXt4ESYRGXgxXHA0hHHwQrA9NZRa4MrQBusPv_zi4cPYkTHQNtlSptJ9n7wCEE/s3005/pexels-artempodrez-5878483_edit_3988774446698123.jpg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/pexels-artempodrez-5878483_edit_3988774446698123.jpg" width="230" height="320" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/pexels-artempodrez-5878483_edit_3988774446698123-xs.jpg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/pexels-artempodrez-5878483_edit_3988774446698123-sm.jpg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/pexels-artempodrez-5878483_edit_3988774446698123-md.jpg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/pexels-artempodrez-5878483_edit_3988774446698123-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/pexels-artempodrez-5878483_edit_3988774446698123-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/26/responsive/pexels-artempodrez-5878483_edit_3988774446698123-2xl.jpg 1600w"></a></div>
<p> </p>
<p>As we navigate this unprecedented public health crisis, it is essential that we have strong, trustworthy institutions that prioritize the safety and well-being of the public above all else. The EMA must step up and provide the clear, evidence-based guidance and leadership that is so desperately needed in this time of uncertainty and fear. Only by putting public health first and earning back the trust of the people can we hope to overcome this pandemic and build a safer, more resilient future.</p>
<p><i>Healthy' doctor, 32, dies after rare severe reaction to AstraZeneca</i></p>
<figure class="post__video"><video loading="lazy" width="450" height="225" controls="controls" data-mce-fragment="1">
<source src="https://rr4---sn-8qj-i5o6d.googlevideo.com/videoplayback?expire=1720706692&amp;ei=BHaPZqK0EK-E2OMPyZC9cA&amp;ip=14.241.62.235&amp;id=71e661a7050a7a50&amp;itag=18&amp;source=blogger&amp;xpc=Egho7Zf3LnoBAQ%3D%3D&amp;mh=ML&amp;mm=31&amp;mn=sn-8qj-i5o6d&amp;ms=au&amp;mv=m&amp;mvi=4&amp;pcm2cms=yes&amp;pl=24&amp;susc=bl&amp;eaua=oB8_rE-J5es&amp;mime=video/mp4&amp;vprv=1&amp;dur=161.541&amp;lmt=1714469017675856&amp;mt=1720677424&amp;txp=1311224&amp;sparams=expire,ei,ip,id,itag,source,xpc,susc,eaua,mime,vprv,dur,lmt&amp;sig=AJfQdSswRQIgAIpgx3bbsFfiQwpNWjqrzSjVXCRgpKdJoNyzz68l4jQCIQCxfCSuEv4eDU8FT9vCvTjvuZEYSMCXu-DG0d6NYiw8eA%3D%3D&amp;lsparams=mh,mm,mn,ms,mv,mvi,pcm2cms,pl&amp;lsig=AHlkHjAwRQIgRwpvlW20WeEz5vIbW4LsusGaHXM6aCmb8DfUui7orYwCIQCkdEzXkjG395fshJfbtElN0VEghR7tqRkBTe3kWF42pQ%3D%3D&amp;cpn=2fCswR9Rx2k4Tt9r&amp;c=WEB_EMBEDDED_PLAYER&amp;cver=1.20240708.01.00" /></video></figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Privacy Policy</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tipeas</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://tipeas.com/privacy-policy.html"/>
        <id>http://tipeas.com/privacy-policy.html</id>

        <updated>2024-04-25T04:50:00+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     Introduction This Privacy Policy ("Policy") describes how Tipeas.com ("Company", "we", "us", or "Tipeas") collects, uses, and discloses your personal information when you access and use the Tipeas.com website (the "Website"). This Policy applies to the Website and all services, features, content, and functionalities offered on&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p> <strong>Introduction</strong></p>
<p>This Privacy Policy ("Policy") describes how Tipeas.com ("Company", "we", "us", or "Tipeas") collects, uses, and discloses your personal information when you access and use the Tipeas.com website (the "Website"). This Policy applies to the Website and all services, features, content, and functionalities offered on or through the Website.</p>
<p><strong>Definitions</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Personal Information</strong><span class="citation-0"> means </span><span class="citation-0 citation-1 citation-end-0">any information that can be used to identify an individual, including but not limited to name,</span><span class="citation-1 citation-end-1"> email address, postal address,</span> phone number, social security number, financial and health information.</li>
<li><strong>Aggregated Data</strong> means information that has been anonymized so that it is no longer linked to a specific individual.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Collection of Personal Information</strong></p>
<p>We collect Personal Information from you when you register for an account, use the Website, contact us, or engage in other activities on the Website. The Personal Information we collect may include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Your name</li>
<li>Your email address</li>
<li>Your password</li>
<li>Your postal address</li>
<li>Your phone number</li>
<li>Your payment information</li>
<li>Information about your use of the Website, such as your IP address, web browser, and operating system</li>
<li>Content you create and share on the Website</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Use of Personal Information</strong></p>
<p>We use your Personal Information for the following purposes:</p>
<ul>
<li>To provide and manage your account</li>
<li>To improve and personalize your experience on the Website</li>
<li>To contact you about your account, the Website, and our other services</li>
<li>To send you marketing and promotional communications, if you consent to receive them</li>
<li>To conduct market research and analysis</li>
<li>To protect the security and integrity of the Website</li>
<li>To comply with applicable laws and regulations</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Disclosure of Personal <span class="citation-2">Information</span></strong></p>
<p><span class="citation-2">We may disclose your Personal Information to third parties in the following circumstances:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ul>
<li><span class="citation-2 citation-end-2">With your consent</span></li>
<li>When we believe disclosure is necessary to comply with applicable laws or regulations, or to enforce our Terms of Service or other agreements with you</li>
<li><span class="citation-3">To protect our rights, property, or safety, or the rights, property, or safety of others</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li><span class="citation-3 citation-end-3">To third-party service providers who</span> help us operate the Website, such as web hosting providers and payment processors</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Your Choices</strong></p>
<p>You can control how we collect, use, and disclose your Personal Information by taking the following steps:</p>
<ul>
<li>Change your account settings</li>
<li>Unsubscribe from receiving marketing communications from us</li>
<li>Contact us to request deletion of your Personal Information</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Data Security</strong></p>
<p><span class="citation-4 citation-end-4">We implement appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use, disclosure,</span> <span class="citation-5 citation-end-5">alteration, or destruction. However, no security measures are perfect, and we cannot guarantee that your Personal Information</span> will not be accessed, used, or disclosed by unauthorized parties.</p>
<p><strong>Your Rights</strong></p>
<p><span class="citation-6 citation-end-6">You have the right to access, rectify, erase, and restrict the processing of your Personal Information. You also have the right</span> to object to the collection and use of your Personal Information. To exercise these rights, please contact us at [email protected]</p>
<p><strong>Changes to this Policy</strong></p>
<p>We may change this Policy at any time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the updated version of this Policy on the Website. You should check this Website periodically for any changes to this Policy.</p>
<p><strong>Contact Us</strong></p>
<p>If you have any questions about this Policy, please contact us at [email protected]</p>
<p><strong>Compliance with GDPR</strong></p>
<p>Tipeas.com is committed to complying with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) of the European Union. Here's how we comply with GDPR:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Lawful basis for processing:</strong> We only collect and use your Personal Information based on a lawful basis, such as your consent, to fulfill a contract, or to comply with legal obligations.</li>
<li><strong>Data minimization:</strong> We only collect the Personal Information that is necessary for the purposes outlined in this Policy.</li>
<li><strong>Storage limitation:</strong> We will only retain your Personal Information for as long as necessary for the purposes outlined in this Policy, or as required by law.</li>
<li><strong>Data integrity and confidentiality:</strong> <span class="citation-7">We implement appropriate </span><span class="citation-7 citation-8 citation-end-7">technical and organizational measures to protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use, disclosure,</span><span class="citation-8 citation-end-8"> alteration, or destruction.</span></li>
<li><strong>Data subject rights:</strong> We respect your right to access, rectify, erase, and restrict the processing of your Personal Information. You also have the right to object to the collection and use of your Personal Information, and the right to data portability.</li>
<li><strong>Data breach notification:</strong> We will notify you and the relevant authorities in the event of a data breach.</li>
<li><strong>Data Protection Officer (DPO):</strong> We have appointed a DPO who is responsible for overseeing our GDPR compliance.</li>
</ul>
<p>We are committed to protecting your privacy and complying with all of the requirements of GDPR.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A Chaotic World: Script for the Rise of a New Monarch?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tipeas</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://tipeas.com/a-chaotic-world-script-for-the-rise-of-a-new-monarch.html"/>
        <id>http://tipeas.com/a-chaotic-world-script-for-the-rise-of-a-new-monarch.html</id>
        <media:content url="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/pexels-ken123films-616852-2.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="USA"/>
            <category term="Putin"/>
            <category term="Politics"/>
            <category term="Israel"/>
            <category term="Iran"/>
            <category term="Conspiracy"/>
            <category term="Conflict"/>
            <category term="Chaos"/>

        <updated>2024-04-25T04:15:00+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/pexels-ken123films-616852-2.jpg" alt="" />
                    The world is in chaos. Putin's relentless terrorist attacks spread fear everywhere. The escalating violence and conflict between Israel and Iran threaten to ignite a regional war. These developments have led many to ask: Is this all part of a grand plan leading to the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/pexels-ken123films-616852-2.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p style="text-align: justify;">The world is in chaos. Putin's relentless terrorist attacks spread fear everywhere. The escalating violence and conflict between Israel and Iran threaten to ignite a regional war. These developments have led many to ask: Is this all part of a grand plan leading to the rise of a new world empire?</p>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiWWKsGWc8RI6L7bwCpP97AniRvRRk32BNC4HBalo7Q-HWdbV0iwjwmrie4JEB2nzRIvpCmUzuskk8KAk_5UP8Cng5lwKZD9j-zcyAKpxPEpb07mLvv2aQ26YEUcOAQL_ihz8Ic7vXBV7Igm8e2E7NVXHe5PXG9-2bQYqF1hsmAW9hKTObN7p9PTWdXIBU/s5184/pexels-ken123films-616852.jpg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/pexels-ken123films-616852.jpg" width="400" height="266" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-ken123films-616852-xs.jpg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-ken123films-616852-sm.jpg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-ken123films-616852-md.jpg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-ken123films-616852-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-ken123films-616852-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-ken123films-616852-2xl.jpg 1600w"></a></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Let's look at the facts:</p>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhtdfD06Je2xQkUS7mDsaT4kPYJHDuHGRJ3f-TUDDmFiDvm_0clcdYV_KcBBW0r5XSq9yI3ZMNssXziQXA0qBOgGWjO5B5IiijlML3H1bx2l36G0ZMPfTWDwmej57pGv-tB5kTsZoFIUNQuCwiePv_En_FFL71OpzRrybOW7qLNDwixnqp4H74JvLiVWs4/s5184/pexels-sima-ghaffarzadeh-164970869-11322895.jpg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/pexels-sima-ghaffarzadeh-164970869-11322895.jpg" width="266" height="400" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-sima-ghaffarzadeh-164970869-11322895-xs.jpg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-sima-ghaffarzadeh-164970869-11322895-sm.jpg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-sima-ghaffarzadeh-164970869-11322895-md.jpg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-sima-ghaffarzadeh-164970869-11322895-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-sima-ghaffarzadeh-164970869-11322895-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-sima-ghaffarzadeh-164970869-11322895-2xl.jpg 1600w"></a></div>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"> </div>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"><strong style="text-align: left;">Putin's desperate efforts:</strong><span style="text-align: left;"> After many failures in the war in Ukraine, Putin is becoming increasingly aggressive and brutal. The recent terrorist attacks show his desperation and weakness. He is trying to spread fear to cover up his own shortcomings and consolidate power.</span></div>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"> </div>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhZrWBByPDf3EJU5-gKhd7_y8484nDiUwXizaCbrln8zBHyOvUAAzqXojHN5Yf573QnJqMn3X_JlohAUwvgmrbolq-T72Ob5LplD7IMwXREd9j2tu42k_sR98tnRHYE3GvEC-dz6hCGn98Uxkf5QVkoXqvxVOVa320k83Q2ogUxvqV4KwsXpgbeJOQueIQ/s5040/pexels-lara-jameson-8828455.jpg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/pexels-lara-jameson-8828455.jpg" width="400" height="266" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-lara-jameson-8828455-xs.jpg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-lara-jameson-8828455-sm.jpg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-lara-jameson-8828455-md.jpg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-lara-jameson-8828455-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-lara-jameson-8828455-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-lara-jameson-8828455-2xl.jpg 1600w"></a></div>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"> </div>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"><strong style="text-align: left;">Israel-Iran conflict:</strong><span style="text-align: left;"> The long-standing disagreement between the two countries is at risk of escalating into a full-blown war. Such a conflict would be disastrous for the entire region and could spread globally.</span></div>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"><span style="text-align: left;"> </span></div>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjDwuJBGizfgRtTba7WUPwjgtdIpIBgOLM6Xs0Nh9ru5aAnI1C2wLvwX6ZWHiq2NYmRsEP2xZ0q_fy55PjHVO2_2G-X6Dg17y8S3kz4VFxD659LUDG3MZLkPkWzLjhmjRT2lVEjoxjdAcTAgjRTrAq6xnNyrj5qdNFCpQV-q06kG9QHDeDHSo8P1eTGYdk/s2000/pexels-pixabay-208724.jpg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/pexels-pixabay-208724.jpg" width="400" height="280" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-pixabay-208724-xs.jpg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-pixabay-208724-sm.jpg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-pixabay-208724-md.jpg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-pixabay-208724-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-pixabay-208724-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/30/responsive/pexels-pixabay-208724-2xl.jpg 1600w"></a></div>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"> </div>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"><strong style="text-align: left;">The rise of the United States:</strong><span style="text-align: left;"> In the midst of a chaotic world, the United States is once again asserting its power and influence. The US is actively involved in international crises, acting as a mediator and providing military aid to allies.</span></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">These developments lead many to believe that the world is heading towards a breaking point, where a new power will rise and take leadership. And the United States, with its abundant resources, powerful military, and extensive experience in resolving international crises, is seen as the most likely candidate for this position.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">However, this scenario also carries many risks. A world dominated by the US could lead to oppression, injustice, and loss of freedom for many nations. The risk of war and conflict would also increase.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Is this the script that the "masters" of the world are setting up? America, was once again given the throne to be the sword of the masters. Or are these just random events in a world full of instability? The answer to this question remains open. However, it is important that we are aware of the potential risks and work together to build a peaceful and just world for all.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>4Q Model</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tipeas</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://tipeas.com/4q-model.html"/>
        <id>http://tipeas.com/4q-model.html</id>
        <media:content url="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/35/4Q-model-2.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Job"/>
            <category term="Economy"/>

        <updated>2023-11-30T09:46:00+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/35/4Q-model-2.png" alt="" />
                    In the years of one's life, everyone must face decisions about the future path of their career. Choosing which company or business to work for and develop for the future is a significant decision that impacts one's life. However, how many of us can truly&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/35/4Q-model-2.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <div class="separator" style="clear: both;">
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: inherit; font-size: large;"> </span></div>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: inherit; font-size: large;"><span style="text-align: left;">In the </span><span style="text-align: left;">years of one's life, everyone must face decisions about the future path of their career. Choosing which company or business to work for and develop for the future is a significant decision that impacts one's life. However, how many of us can truly understand and choose in a way that aligns with our desires and future plans?</span></span></div>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/35/4Q-model.png" alt="" width="552" height="521" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/35/responsive/4Q-model-xs.png 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/35/responsive/4Q-model-sm.png 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/35/responsive/4Q-model-md.png 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/35/responsive/4Q-model-lg.png 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/35/responsive/4Q-model-xl.png 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/35/responsive/4Q-model-2xl.png 1600w"></figure></div>
</div>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both;"><span style="font-family: inherit; font-size: large;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">Upon graduating and leaving the school environment, everyone is enthusiastic about their new job. However, after a few years, we quickly fall into the crisis of boredom, stagnation, and imbalance in life.</span></span></div>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both;"><span style="font-family: inherit; font-size: large;"><br>Browsing through websites and forums, there are many career-oriented articles, advice on choosing professions, and talent recruitment introductions. Still, there is a scarcity of sharing about choosing a career based on personal goals and its reciprocal impact on life.<br><br>In a person's life, there are always four factors that make up personal life:<br><br>1. Health<br><br>2. Time<br><br>3. Personal priorities<br><br>4. Ultimate goals<br><br>In work, there are four factors that contribute to the success of a career:<br><br>1. Responsibility and achievements<br><br>2. Risks<br><br>3. Abilities<br><br>4. Industry<br><br>These eight factors interact to create a picture of one's career and life<br><br>Health and Time:<br><br>These are two fundamental life factors that are often underestimated. When young and just starting a job, we can work 12 hours a day and six days a week. However, after a few years, with age and family, if we continue to maintain such work, we will notice a decline in health and lack of time for other life matters. We will feel imbalanced and exhausted.<br><br>Responsibility and Significant Achievements:<br><br>This implies a large income, which also takes away a lot of time and health.<br><br>Personal Priorities:<br><br>Apart from work, an individual has a personal life with accompanying values that are prioritized. For example, family, social relationships, personal hobbies, etc. An employer should not assume that an employee who devotes a lot of effort and mind to work will always have the highest productivity. In reality, if they are someone who prioritizes family, frequently engages in arguments with their spouse, or has strained relationships, with such a mindset at work, their efficiency will undoubtedly decrease rapidly. No one can work efficiently when they feel that the values they prioritize in life are diminishing.<br><br>Abilities:<br><br>Each person has their own abilities, which can be innate or developed through learning. Working in line with one's natural talent always brings excitement and easily achieves high performance. Even if we lack a certain ability, we can train to develop it. However, no matter how beneficial a job is for our abilities, it always takes away as much time and personal priorities.<br><br>Example:<br><br>Multinational companies valued at over 2 billion USD are excellent environments for fresh graduates. There, you can quickly learn advanced business methods and top-notch working procedures. However, it will take a considerable amount of your time and life priorities.<br><br>Startups absorb almost all your time and personal life funds. However, in return, you can learn how to build your own business for the future.<br><br>Risks:<br><br>There are three main types of risks:<br><br>1. Business failure and industry recession.<br><br>2. Geographical scope required by the job.<br><br>3. Financial risks.<br><br>The first is the most direct but also the most challenging to evaluate. For example, the aviation and transportation industry is easily affected by fluctuations in oil prices.<br><br>Startups have a very high risk of failure. According to statistics in the United States and Italy, 80% of startups go bankrupt within the first two years. However, going back to the startup example above, when the risk is assessed, and a decision is made after careful analysis, working for a startup is no longer a gamble. You are betting on a potential project that can help you achieve your ultimate goal faster.<br><br>Jobs requiring frequent long-distance travel increase the risk to both health and personal life.<br><br>Financial instability and debt will make us feel stressed and mentally unfree. At that point, we are willing to take risks to increase income or easily lower requirements to increase the chances of selection. This poses a significant risk to the long-term future of your career.<br><br>Industry:<br><br>When bored and stuck with the current job, we tend to want to switch to another industry or move within the same industry but to a more extensive environment. Two people are both sales managers. One manages the Chinese market, and the other oversees the markets of Indonesia, Thailand, and the Philippines. The colleague in my technical field, after many years working with machinery, wanted to change industries. They studied for a business management degree or ventured into financial fields. Instead of doing so, choosing a similar industry (horizontal) or a related one (vertical) allows you to leverage your existing experience and knowledge to make higher strides in development. Expanding your industry always takes away a lot of time and may not promise a bright future.<br><br>Ultimate Goals:<br><br>Retiring early at 40 and traveling around the world, or establishing your own school, operating and teaching what you want to pass on to future generations. Whatever it is, we all need a final goal that has meaning for ourselves. It doesn't have to be immediate. Still, making choices for the current career and short-term goals that will help you achieve the final goal later is ideal. Without goals, you won't achieve anything.<br></span></div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Why did Singapore achieve wealth and development so quickly?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tipeas</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://tipeas.com/why-did-singapore-achieve-wealth-and-development-so-quickly.html"/>
        <id>http://tipeas.com/why-did-singapore-achieve-wealth-and-development-so-quickly.html</id>
        <media:content url="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/37/pexels-media-1907049-1686477858904-2.jpeg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Singapore"/>
            <category term="Public Policy"/>
            <category term="Government company"/>
            <category term="Economy"/>

        <updated>2023-11-29T07:09:00+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/37/pexels-media-1907049-1686477858904-2.jpeg" alt="" />
                    History of Singapore Singapore is an island nation in Southeast Asia, close to Malaysia and Indonesia. Singapore was a British colony since 1819. The British established military bases and a seaport, indirectly shaping Singapore's economy around transit trade: Western goods, raw materials from Southeast Asia,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/37/pexels-media-1907049-1686477858904-2.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <div><figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/37/pexels-media-1907049-1686477858904.jpeg" alt="" width="1280" height="853" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/37/responsive/pexels-media-1907049-1686477858904-xs.jpeg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/37/responsive/pexels-media-1907049-1686477858904-sm.jpeg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/37/responsive/pexels-media-1907049-1686477858904-md.jpeg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/37/responsive/pexels-media-1907049-1686477858904-lg.jpeg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/37/responsive/pexels-media-1907049-1686477858904-xl.jpeg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/37/responsive/pexels-media-1907049-1686477858904-2xl.jpeg 1600w"></figure></div>
<div><span style="font-family: Be Vietnam Pro;"> </span></div>
<div><span style="font-family: Be Vietnam Pro;"><strong>History of Singapore</strong></span></div>
<div><span style="font-family: Be Vietnam Pro;"><strong> </strong></span></div>
<p><span style="font-family: Noto Sans Tai Viet;">Singapore is an island nation in Southeast Asia, close to Malaysia and Indonesia. Singapore was a British colony since 1819. The British established military bases and a seaport, indirectly shaping Singapore's economy around transit trade: Western goods, raw materials from Southeast Asia, and opium. When Britain granted self-governance in 1959 and withdrew its military, Singapore faced challenges: unemployment, lack of housing and healthcare, poverty, and underdeveloped education. However, Singapore quickly overcame these challenges and rose to become a leading economically developed country in Asia, achieving the "Asian Tiger" miracle. Its per capita GDP surpassed some Western countries by 1994, such as Australia, Canada, and the UK. In 2013, Singapore ranked 9th in the United Nations Development Programme's Human Development Index, surpassing all other Asian countries.</span></p>
<figure class="post__video"><video loading="lazy" width="450" height="225" controls="controls" data-mce-fragment="1">
<source src="https://videos.pexels.com/video-files/5189561/5189561-hd_1280_720_25fps.mp4" type="video/mp4" /></video></figure>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; text-align: center;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Singapore from above</span></p>
<h3 dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 4pt; margin-top: 14pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Challenges in Singapore</span></h3>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 12pt; margin-top: 12pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">The small land area led to a small domestic market and resource scarcity. The population is diverse, primarily descendants of immigrants from China (76.6%), India (6.4%), and Malaysia (14.7%). Ethnic tensions arose in the 1950s-1960s. There was no local industrial capital, and a lack of defense forces faced external threats.</span></p>
<figure class="post__video"><video loading="lazy" width="450" height="225" controls="controls" data-mce-fragment="1">
<source src="https://videos.pexels.com/video-files/4583055/4583055-hd_1920_1080_25fps.mp4" type="video/mp4" /></video></figure>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; text-align: center;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">People of Singapore</span></p>
<h3 dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 4pt; margin-top: 14pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Addressing Challenges</span></h3>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 15pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Singapore didn't rely on local capital like Japan, South Korea, and Taiwan but depended on state capital and multinational corporations to develop the economy.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 15pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">The Singaporean government, led by the People's Action Party, established Regulatory Boards. These are quasi-governmental organizations, separate from the civil service, but still within the investment portfolio of the ministries. Managed by boards comprising government representatives, private sector forces, professional groups, and interest groups, these regulatory boards were created to oversee state-owned or partially state-owned enterprises. They covered all sectors: industry, commerce, finance-banking, insurance, healthcare, housing, infrastructure, and postal-telecommunications, and transportation.</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro;"> </span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 12pt; margin-top: 12pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Singapore's state-owned enterprises differ significantly from those in other countries. Profitable operations are expected (excluding healthcare, education, and public housing for low-income individuals). If a state-owned enterprise incurs losses, it doesn't receive subsidies or bailouts and must shut down. These enterprises are managed by highly qualified professional teams with competitive salaries compared to the private sector.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 12pt; margin-top: 12pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Notably, the Economic Development Board played a crucial role in attracting investment and developing industries to address unemployment. And the Housing and Development Board tackled housing shortages.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 12pt; margin-top: 12pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">In the initial phase, the Economic Development Board successfully attracted investment and formed joint ventures with foreign companies. The board's tasks included developing infrastructure, industrial estates, managing the supply of quality labor, and providing capital or sponsoring loans. Singapore continuously created jobs and acquired technical expertise, gradually moving towards owning knowledge and technology.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 12pt; margin-top: 12pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">In the later stage, the Economic Development Board succeeded in shifting from labor-intensive industries to knowledge-intensive ones (relocating labor-intensive industries to Malaysia and Indonesia). Success was found in export-oriented strategies and overseas investment. In the 1970s, services became the second pillar of the economy alongside manufacturing.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 12pt; margin-top: 12pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">The Housing and Development Board achieved a remarkable feat unmatched elsewhere. From 1960 to 1985, 84% of the population had public housing. In 1968, the government enacted the Central Provident Fund (CPF) Savings Scheme. Both employers and employees had to contribute a fixed amount to the fund (a mandatory form of insurance). Citizens could use the CPF for housing, education, and healthcare. The CPF was tightly managed by a regulatory council.</span></p>
<figure class="post__video"><video loading="lazy" width="450" height="225" controls="controls" data-mce-fragment="1">
<source src="https://videos.pexels.com/video-files/20746131/20746131-uhd_2560_1440_50fps.mp4" type="video/mp4" /></video></figure>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; text-align: center;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; vertical-align: baseline;">Changi Airport</span></p>
<h3 dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 4pt; margin-top: 14pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Flexibility of Singapore's Economy</span></h3>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 12pt; margin-top: 12pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">During the economic slowdown of the 1990s, Singapore astutely transitioned between globalization and regionalization by establishing the Malaysia-Singapore-Indonesia economic growth triangle in 1989. They reallocated labor, leveraging the advantages of the labor force in the remaining two countries, allowing Singapore to focus on developing a knowledge and technology-based economy. They expanded regionalization plans to surrounding areas through industrial zones in Vietnam, China, and India.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 12pt; margin-top: 12pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">China: Suzhou Industrial Park, Tianjin Eco-city; Indonesia: Batamindo Industrial Park, Bintan Industrial Estate; India: Bangalore IT Park, Sentosa City; Vietnam: Vietnam-Singapore Industrial Park, and more.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 12pt; margin-top: 12pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">In 1987, the government began divesting and embarked on privatization, creating conditions for private sector participation in various industries: telecommunications, services, finance, insurance. The motivations were:</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 15pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">1.Strengthening the role of the private sector in economic development.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">2.Reducing competition between the government and private sector, leading to the second motivation.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">3.Transforming Singapore into an international financial center through the development of the stock market.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 15pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">The government would allocate funds to invest in new, potentially profitable sectors where the private sector couldn't participate. Examples include biomedical sciences, interactive media and digital technology, environmental protection and water technologies, etc.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 12pt; margin-top: 12pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">During the Asian financial crisis in 1997, Singapore shifted to globalization. The government encouraged companies to expand into global markets: Europe, North America, South Asia, the Middle East.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 12pt; margin-top: 12pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Several state-owned companies became crucial global players in various industries: Singtel (telecommunications), Keppel Corporation and Sembcorp Industries (marine transport), CapitaLand (real estate development), DBS Group Holdings (finance), Singapore Airlines (air passenger transport), Neptune Orient Lines (shipping), and more.</span></p>
<h3 dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 4pt; margin-top: 14pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Role of Temasek Holding and GIC</span></h3>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;">Initially, Temasek Holding played a role in managing the state's shares in various companies, overseeing and reporting the financial status of these companies to the government.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;">Later on, the role of Temasek Holding shifted towards promoting the economic development of Singapore, achieving long-term stable profits to enhance the national assets.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;">Temasek maintains a global investment portfolio, with a relatively low allocation of 28% to Singapore. The remaining focus is on Asia outside Singapore, Europe, North America, Australia, and New Zealand, as of 2015. Temasek invested 70% in Asia and distributed the remaining 30% across Europe, North America, Australia, New Zealand, and Central Asia.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;">In 2015, according to the Sovereign Wealth Fund Institute's ranking, Temasek Holdings, with assets valued at $1.936 trillion USD, stood as the world's largest sovereign wealth fund. Another sovereign wealth fund from Singapore, GIC, was ranked eighth with assets totaling $344 billion USD.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;">GIC, established by the Singapore government with a surplus foreign exchange reserves, receives an annual discretionary transfer from the government to augment its capital. In contrast, Temasek is entirely self-funded, drawing its capital from main sources such as company dividends, proceeds from divestments, investment fund profits, and the issuance of long and short-term debt.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro;"><span style="font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;">Unlike Temasek, GIC is prohibited by law from investing in Singapore. GIC's investment portfolio is also less concentrated in Asia compared to Temasek. In 2015, GIC's geographical allocation of investment portfolios was as follows: the Americas 43% (U.S. 34%), Europe 25%, Asia 30%, and Australia 2% (source:</span><a href="http://www.gic.com.sg/images/pdf/GIC_Report_2015.pdf"><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;"> http://www.gic.com.sg/images/pdf/GIC_Report_2015.pdf</span></a><span style="font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;">).</span></span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;">This strategy serves as insurance for Singapore's economy. On one hand, it reduces risks for the investment portfolio originating from Singapore, and on the other hand, it secures foreign capital to stabilize and develop the economy.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;">These two national investment funds play crucial roles in maintaining and safeguarding the long-term financial stability of the domestic economy. GIC, acting as a reserve currency investor, is vital for protecting Singapore's economy from financial crises and preventing interference from the government and multilateral institutions in Singapore's economy, similar to the role played by the IMF in neighboring countries during the 1997-98 Asian financial crisis, leading to reduced national sovereignty.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;">In conclusion, in Singapore, the state acts as an entrepreneur. State-owned enterprises follow market principles and operate efficiently. Loss-making enterprises are not bailed out but are required to close. Since its establishment in the 1960s and 1970s, Singapore's state capitalism has continuously evolved. On one hand, the state has withdrawn from certain economic sectors; on the other hand, it has expanded into other areas with the goal of Singapore's economic development. The result is a continuous restructuring of Singapore's state capitalism. The government decides to privatize some or all companies not only because they are loss-making entities but also because state participation is no longer necessary in specific sectors.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;">Since the 1980s, many profitable state-owned enterprises, professionally managed by Singapore, have expanded beyond the city-state's borders, becoming significant entities in their respective fields in the global economy.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;">References:</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;">Title: "The Successful Model of State Capitalism: Singapore"</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt; padding: 0pt 0pt 15pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;">Author: Katalin Völgyi</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro; font-size: 12pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline;">Published in 2019</span></p>
<p><span style="background-color: white; font-family: Be Vietnam Pro;"> </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Why is sex tourism so prevalent in Thailand?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tipeas</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://tipeas.com/why-is-sex-tourism-so-prevalent-in-thailand.html"/>
        <id>http://tipeas.com/why-is-sex-tourism-so-prevalent-in-thailand.html</id>
        <media:content url="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/38/pexels-media-50541-1686559310126-2.jpeg" medium="image" />
            <category term="sex tourism"/>
            <category term="human rights"/>
            <category term="exploiting women"/>
            <category term="employment"/>
            <category term="Thailand"/>
            <category term="Economy"/>

        <updated>2023-11-29T06:39:00+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/38/pexels-media-50541-1686559310126-2.jpeg" alt="" />
                    The sex tourism industry. Such terms are used to refer to the sex tourism industry in Thailand. For Western men with average incomes, it is not cheap to take a long two-week vacation from Europe or the United States to Thailand. So what makes Thailand&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/38/pexels-media-50541-1686559310126-2.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <div><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/38/pexels-media-50541-1686559310126.jpeg" alt="" width="1280" height="960" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/38/responsive/pexels-media-50541-1686559310126-xs.jpeg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/38/responsive/pexels-media-50541-1686559310126-sm.jpeg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/38/responsive/pexels-media-50541-1686559310126-md.jpeg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/38/responsive/pexels-media-50541-1686559310126-lg.jpeg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/38/responsive/pexels-media-50541-1686559310126-xl.jpeg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/38/responsive/pexels-media-50541-1686559310126-2xl.jpeg 1600w"></figure></div>
<div><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 12pt; font-weight: bold; color: var(--text-primary-color);">The sex tourism industry.</span></div>
<div>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Such terms are used to refer to the sex tourism industry in Thailand.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">For Western men with average incomes, it is not cheap to take a long two-week vacation from Europe or the United States to Thailand. So what makes Thailand an attractive destination? The answer is sex tourism. It is a true capitalist industry, based on the bodies of Thai women. It includes the Thai government, national and international travel agencies, multinational restaurant chains, international hotels, and international airlines. All contribute to driving this billion-dollar industry each year.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">The question is: Why has Thailand, a predominantly Buddhist country with over 3000 temples, become the hub of the international sex trade?</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">The answer is complex, involving both internal and external factors, including what the media highlights and overlooks.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">External Factors</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">The U.S. established Thailand as a military base during the Vietnam War. Sex services for U.S. soldiers were a significant project carried out in Thailand, known as R&amp;R. This laid the groundwork for the later development of the sex tourism industry in Thailand.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Internal Factors</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Thailand has a history of slavery, where the value of women is much lower than that of men. This created conditions for slave owners to operate in Thailand from early ancient dynasties. In 1909, Thailand abolished slavery, leading these female slaves to enter the sex trade.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Thailand's religion is Buddhism, but it is deeply influenced by Hinduism and Brahmanism with a strong male-centric philosophy. Despite having numerous temples, Thai Buddhists are less imbued with the philosophical teachings of Buddhism. Buddhism in Thailand is reserved for men, and women are considered to have no spiritual destiny to become monks. When a man reaches a certain age, participating in a temple retreat is seen as a rite of passage and societal prestige. This is done to accumulate merit for parents. However, Thai women are not allowed to do this, relying on the duty of financially supporting their parents through direct or labor-exchange jobs, considered lower than men's. Even when women enter political positions, their presence is of little significance. In the workplace, women's income is consistently lower than men's.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Northern and Northeastern Thailand are the poorest regions, deliberately maintained by government policies that make access to education difficult. Agriculture is underdeveloped, with no government support and no favorable loans.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Thai women in these areas have few options to fulfill their filial duties. One is to work in industrial factories with low labor costs and virtually no welfare. This policy aims to keep labor cheap and female workers retiring before the age of 30. The other option is to migrate to Bangkok and join the sex industry with less pressure and higher earnings.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Here, they face the fear of going with strangers, whether white or Japanese, not knowing what they will do. The government and police do not legalize prostitution, disallowing bars to operate as brothels, but turning a blind eye to bars charging a small fee (200 baht) to lead customers outside. In return, the bars receive a protection fee.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">In the northern regions, where moral and cultural standards are stricter, when a girl returns home with beautiful clothes and a decent house for her parents, money for her younger brother's education and seed costs, her virtues will overshadow the source of her money. Many girls return and actively become recruiters in their hometowns. Many companies come and provide loans to families, in exchange for their daughters joining this industry. Many parents are deceived into believing that their daughters will have good jobs. However, many parents sell their daughters to brothel owners or human trafficking agents.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Western media blames the U.S. for making prostitution widespread here, but they fail to acknowledge it as a real industry, with the main product being the bodies and services provided by Thai girls. The profits from tourism, airlines, hotels, and brokers flow into the pockets of capitalists and the government.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Another factor not mentioned by the media is Thai men. In history, the culture in northern and northeastern Thailand penalized men for inappropriate sexual behavior, imposing fines. This is no different from allowing men to engage in extramarital sex, for which they would pay a fee. A form of prostitution.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">The percentage of Thai men who regularly or irregularly use sex services is significant, with figures as high as 84% presented by the West to criticize: they brought prostitution to Thailand and degraded the country. But we need to ask: How can a country allow women to rely on prostitution as an economic pillar when its men do not agree?</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">Apart from female prostitution, there is also a significant portion of male sex workers. Publicly presented cultural products emphasize that it is gay male prostitution. It may be that investigating male prostitution is considered sensitive and inferior, making it difficult. In reality, many male sex workers have female clients.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">In conclusion, the reasons why Thai women enter prostitution are complex. Their voices are often absent, recounted by authors and journalists in surveys and interviews. The opinions of male sex workers are also lacking.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 11pt; vertical-align: baseline;">However, it is not without the following factors. The historical and religious context is unfavorable to Thai women and normalizes prostitution. The duty of Thai women to bear, combined with the economic background, unbalanced education between urban and rural areas, leaves them with very few choices. The government implements policies to indirectly sustain the sex industry, considering it an incentive to attract capital. Domestic and international capitalist organizations actively invest and promote to reap benefits.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<span id="docs-internal-guid-dd5c7c92-7fff-3547-a2df-4616d0b78139"></span></div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Looking back at Thailand economic crisis in 1997</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tipeas</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://tipeas.com/looking-back-at-thailandand039s-economic-crisis-in-1997.html"/>
        <id>http://tipeas.com/looking-back-at-thailandand039s-economic-crisis-in-1997.html</id>
        <media:content url="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/png_20230508_110638_0000-2.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="inflationary"/>
            <category term="Thailand"/>
            <category term="IMF"/>
            <category term="George Soros"/>
            <category term="Economy"/>
            <category term="Crisis"/>
            <category term="ASIA"/>

        <updated>2023-05-08T04:25:00+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/png_20230508_110638_0000-2.png" alt="" />
                    The year 1997 marked the Asian financial crisis, the focal point of which was the 1997 Thailand crisis. The context of Thailand and Vietnam now has many similarities. Tipeas will present the Thai crisis so that we can have a broader perspective and draw lessons&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/png_20230508_110638_0000-2.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"> </span></p>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgdAGiKe75coiisplVS_AkSQ6FmgWGiA40LQHk2vfT6AT1P9Of-9ttwVWpOLUFRpY0uN84fyJC-v70a3mBzhGjf0bmMGZUvtEjexfW774W_Pjjlf1-_3UH5XNtHBpz-gmY17Q4SCFACrGYk748IKmMS5qlt36MIMfdAS7gBjASJGiOwQ27tsrPQiPgA/s2000/png_20230508_110638_0000.png" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/png_20230508_110638_0000.png" width="452" height="640" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/png_20230508_110638_0000-xs.png 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/png_20230508_110638_0000-sm.png 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/png_20230508_110638_0000-md.png 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/png_20230508_110638_0000-lg.png 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/png_20230508_110638_0000-xl.png 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/png_20230508_110638_0000-2xl.png 1600w"></span></a></div>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">The year 1997 marked the Asian financial crisis, the focal point of which was the 1997 Thailand crisis. The context of Thailand and Vietnam now has many similarities. Tipeas will present the Thai crisis so that we can have a broader perspective and draw lessons for ourselves.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Origin of Thailand's economic development.</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Before floating about the crisis, let's take a look at Thailand's economy before the crisis. The pre-crisis period from 1960 to 1990 was Thailand's golden growth period. Thai economy at that time was hailed by the media as Asia's new tiger. Before the crisis, no one doubted the growth rate of the Thai economy. This is true before any crisis. Thailand's economic boom is mainly due to the war of the US and its allies in Vietnam. Indeed, the capital that the US has invested in facilities, military systems and bases serving the Vietnam war, has become a direct impetus for Thailand to develop industrial production and tourism. (including legal prostitution for US soldiers). Next is the advantage of the cheapest labor, large land resources, available natural resources. All these factors attract industrial manufacturers, especially the American and Japanese motorcycle and automobile manufacturing industries. All create a picture of industrial exports and rapid economic development.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Crisis happened.</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">The Thai baht depreciated. From 26 Bath to 1 USD, the Thai currency has depreciated to 56 Bath for 1 USD. Lose more than 100% value. The unemployment rate increased to an unprecedented high, exports decreased, the balance of imports and exports was negative for many years.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">The cause of the crisis.</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">The Thai crisis is very specific and it includes many interacting factors. We will present the most complete and intuitive. Consists of two causes: coming from outside and internal within Thailand.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">1. External causes:</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">The first is the emergence of China and India in industrial production. These two countries quickly emerged as manufacturing and export hubs in the global supply chain due to the advantage of cheaper labor. This is also the period when China devalued the yuan to gain export advantage. Meanwhile, the labor cost of Thailand has increased significantly. This makes the price of Thai exports more expensive and less competitive. Along with that, the profit/labor productivity ratio of foreign capitalist companies in Thailand decreased.</span></p>
<table class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" align="center">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiMKsewnO2zV0Ctkcc-DhIqHtRWxBwgxPWk8p3HvKClGpKoiIJEfg4bzy-OYdlODTaNxng0IGu2Y0bntSRdMlm_w-Uwp28wItiXizEC4JesDTuD-0HK-HBJXuwb5YZ2kxwibfdZqleTcqtozgw0qYttoz8rvSHEg3blidG8BXw_z46TDl1qZI8MXdhd/s948/Screenshot_20230424_091438.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><span style="font-size: medium;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/Screenshot_20230424_091438.jpg" width="640" height="266" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/Screenshot_20230424_091438-xs.jpg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/Screenshot_20230424_091438-sm.jpg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/Screenshot_20230424_091438-md.jpg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/Screenshot_20230424_091438-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/Screenshot_20230424_091438-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/Screenshot_20230424_091438-2xl.jpg 1600w"></span></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Percentage of increase in labor productivity and wages, 1990-1995. Source: UNIDO Database (2000).</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Second, the nature of capital companies will fall into a crisis of excess and then recession. Capitalist companies tend to find a developing country (periphery) to produce in order to take advantage of cheap labor and high profit rates. This is the first stage in the development of a capitalist company. Increase production and generate revenue very quickly. Labor productivity increases because of the use of high-tech machinery. Very quickly production will peak and start to be redundant. The result is production cuts, layoffs. To solve this problem, the capitalist state and company will take the second step. That is to create a consumer fund and invest in the development of the environment and infrastructure. They began to raise wages for workers so that workers could use that money to spend on the products that the company created. This happens to some extent, going against the interests of the company, as it reduces profit margins. If infrastructure development is appropriate and effective. The industry in the host country will be expanded and create more jobs.</p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">In Thailand, labor-intensive (labour-intensive) industries such as apparel and footwear, quickly lost their edge to China, India and other emerging Asian nations. As for high-tech industries, with large FDI capital, capital-intensive as well as: automobiles, motorcycles, mechanical engineering, there is no connection with the local industry. Instead, it is closely related to its parent country or the output countries of the product. Effective use of capital and rational investment in infrastructure development is difficult in developing countries. The usual evidence is traffic congestion and the pitted skyline of unfinished skyscrapers. In Thailand is no exception, the step of capital accumulation and infrastructure development has not been successful. So the third step: technology research and development also did not take place. The proof is in the statistics. There are only 0.2 development researchers for every 1000 Thais. It was 0.3 lower than Vietnam at that time. And significantly lower than Singapore and China. The truth is that it is the largest FDI companies in Thailand that devote very little attention to R&amp;D in the country.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">When the competitive environment is fierce, the advantage of cheap labor is lost, and there is a shortage of highly qualified human resources. Domestic industry did not expand. This has consequences: exports fall, unemployment rises, and domestic demand is low. Thailand quickly faced an economic downturn.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">When the Thai economy stood on the brink. Foreign organizations have carried out many attacks on the baht (speculative estimates up to 10 billion USD) to seriously devalue the baht. In most articles, they identified this as the cause and the spur that caused the crisis to occur. However, our view is: the depreciation of the baht is a sign of instability, an inevitable consequence.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">2. Internal causes.</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">The Thai government has liberalized the economy while lacking measures to control and secure it. The central bank of Thailand has lost its self-control and has been manipulated by politicians to introduce unreasonable monetary policy. First, the state deregulates domestic finance and removes constraints on portfolio management, including easing regulations on capital adequacy requirements and allowing commercial banks to Commercial and financial institutions expand their fields of activity (financial institutions can participate in activities that are owned by banks: foreign exchange trading, borrowing and lending). Second, the state lifted most of its foreign exchange controls and opened the Bangkok International Bank Facility, allowing foreign borrowing in foreign currency and conversion to Thai baht, thereby increasing capital inflows. Thailand from countries with lower interest rates. This is further facilitated by the third policy, which is to keep the baht pegged to a basket of currencies (USD, Japanese Yen, German Mark) in which USD has the highest weight, thus making dollar loans become artificially cheap as the dollar appreciates against the yen. Fourth, the state keeps interest rates high and always stabilizes the exchange rate to attract foreign capital. This led to a corollary: USD loans became very attractive and accompanied by high-risk investments.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Foreign investors can get 10-11% interest on such short-term loans. Domestic borrowers are also eager to borrow abroad because the source of money is cheaper and the fixed exchange rate regime makes people think there is no currency risk. Thai businesses that borrow money have found that they can borrow at 5-8% interest rates instead of paying more than 13% when borrowing domestically. They can even make money simply by borrowing abroad and depositing baht in Thailand. As a result, Thailand has borrowed too much abroad. External debt increased from nearly $40 billion in 1992 to $80 billion in March 1997.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Three decades of industrial development have accumulated capital, combined with a flood of USD-denominated investment loans. It all flowed into real estate and stocks. Blow up a giant asset bubble. When the bubble burst, a series of commercial banks and financial institutions collapsed. The central bank raised interest rates on the one hand, and on the other hand pumped money out to rescue these institutions. This further aggravated inflation.</span></p>
<table class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" align="center">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEggIYvOs3oM9135OjLhIZEQRt-wmtvs33z3_j7nzJRuhZ-3eEz34vF4bujThdnjj3x8THrI54_dTpkZzvPA2EFBOf9ih3vcjjL2a8aHMaeTcMQ2fuwTmVWvtghLyG7AkpjuOxuwQ7fiEV_qafE6MsNSSVAZ8tBVXwgRnzzCdZuJTmMFPKzjfUl2VqBN/s1080/Screenshot_20230424_090832.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><span style="font-size: medium;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/Screenshot_20230424_090832.jpg" width="640" height="290" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/Screenshot_20230424_090832-xs.jpg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/Screenshot_20230424_090832-sm.jpg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/Screenshot_20230424_090832-md.jpg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/Screenshot_20230424_090832-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/Screenshot_20230424_090832-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/39/responsive/Screenshot_20230424_090832-2xl.jpg 1600w"></span></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Increasing Value Added, By Sector, 1987-1995. Source: NESDB (1987-95)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Final consequences.</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Thailand has to borrow up to a bailout of about 17 billion USD under the protection of the IMF (of which the IMF 4 billion, Japan 4 billion, China 1 billion, the World Bank and the Asian Development Bank 2.3 billion, the United States does not pay the fee contribute even a little) to support the economy and with it comes a myriad of strict austerity terms. 56/58 financial institutions closed for liquidation. Nationalized four mid-sized banks to sell them to foreign financial institutions namely Bangkok Metropolitan Bank, First City Bank, Siam City Bank and Bangkok Commercial Bank.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Thailand's economy declined rapidly, the import-export balance was negative for many years. However, devaluation of the baht is beneficial for exports. But it is accompanied by the high cost of importing input materials. This leads to higher export prices and low profit margins. Finally, unemployment increased, mainly in the financial sector, real estate, construction and manufacturing industries with high import content. It is estimated that in 1998, about 600,000 people lost their jobs. More specifically, 20000-30000 workers lost their jobs in the financial sector and 300000-40000 construction workers lost their jobs. The car industry has reported nearly 29,000 layoffs. Furthermore, it is estimated that small businesses have lost about 70000 workers, with another 500,000 expected to be unemployed next year.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Comment:</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">The financial and economic crisis of Thailand is a very typical crisis of a developing country. Thailand receives foreign FDI to develop hot manufacturing. However, the policy of capital utilization and reinvestment is not effective. The number of domestic industrial companies is too low. The economy depends on exports. Failing to grasp and develop technology. Leading to a crisis of overcapacity and reduced competitiveness. Capital flows to the wrong place causing waste and asset bubbles. Finally, the wrong economic policy creates more risks and weakens the economic situation. When a crisis begins, weak responses and late interventions lead to severe crises and long-lasting consequences.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"><i>The article references material from:</i></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"><i>Financial Crisis in Thailand: Causes, Procedures and Consequences. LAURIDS S. LAURIDSEN Roskilde University, Denmark.</i></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"><i>Economic crisis in Asia: The case of Thailand. Jim Glassman, Department of Geography, Syracuse University, Syracuse, New York.</i></span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Three principles to protect money in the account.</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tipeas</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://tipeas.com/three-principles-to-protect-money-in-the-account.html"/>
        <id>http://tipeas.com/three-principles-to-protect-money-in-the-account.html</id>
        <media:content url="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/pexels-media-60504-1682704637784-2.jpeg" medium="image" />
            <category term="scams"/>
            <category term="hackers"/>
            <category term="Money"/>
            <category term="Information leaks"/>
            <category term="Infomation security"/>
            <category term="Economy"/>

        <updated>2023-05-08T02:57:00+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/pexels-media-60504-1682704637784-2.jpeg" alt="" />
                    Nowadays, when everyone uses a bank account. Online transactions and card payments take place anywhere. One morning when you wake up, you receive a notice that your account has been completely deducted. Which you do not make those transactions at all. Contacted the bank and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/pexels-media-60504-1682704637784-2.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjAgLJZ1i0JCjGNGGJjF-_-hpizwnZIvkWFRhsXYcvbPpKbGUol2yPyuYE7OFjP5C6G1ELeGJnXFPuQUXDXNqQq4YnIAa8BERCdCpf6bsDsiw1hU3TUa98iMEiGB9OtsxHc4fuZ1h6BRZjvYayQHTt75Wq4dg00KsmrGTxKY9eAl9Gcg_K6cii5YVKo/s1920/pexels-media-60504-1682704637784.jpeg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/pexels-media-60504-1682704637784.jpeg" width="640" height="426" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-60504-1682704637784-xs.jpeg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-60504-1682704637784-sm.jpeg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-60504-1682704637784-md.jpeg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-60504-1682704637784-lg.jpeg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-60504-1682704637784-xl.jpeg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-60504-1682704637784-2xl.jpeg 1600w"></a></div>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Nowadays, when everyone uses a bank account. Online transactions and card payments take place anywhere. One morning when you wake up, you receive a notice that your account has been completely deducted. Which you do not make those transactions at all. Contacted the bank and they said all transactions were valid. How do you keep yourself from falling into that situation? Here are some very simple principles that can help you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"> </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Rule number one: minimize risk.</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">You should use at least two accounts of two different banks, with two different phone numbers. An account is only used to store money. Do not make any online transactions, swipe cards, swipe cards, link e-wallets. This account is definitely not public, even the phone number registered with this account needs to be kept private. The second account is only used for online transactions, swiping cards, etc. In this account, only the minimum balance is maintained, not exceeding 10% of the amount you have. Just use it up, move it back in when needed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">For using payment cards, debit cards, credit cards. Even if you issue a card on an account that is only used for online transactions, it contains little money. To ensure safety in case you lose your card. You should remember the last three numbers on the card number. Then use a hard object to erase the three embossed numbers on the card. That way crooks can't use your card.</span></p>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgRPBdNHxfOvzn3hfulOHB3_-sK1OF0LNLJrTYbLnfvMDQEdcZlD7KqlX74_uZ-fUEBmyec5QJ8SrKbQeBW9pW5H3AwjlNxB9AHzFuNmrZD6IRgdBer9MZgg4lGtl-vDS4ULoNLBJ2PvzICBeEYF5Zxoo3WEne0nB5Rj7vMMTxOnY7UqKICY2FGGpH0/s1920/pexels-media-259200-1682704558942.jpeg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/pexels-media-259200-1682704558942.jpeg" width="640" height="426" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-259200-1682704558942-xs.jpeg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-259200-1682704558942-sm.jpeg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-259200-1682704558942-md.jpeg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-259200-1682704558942-lg.jpeg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-259200-1682704558942-xl.jpeg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-259200-1682704558942-2xl.jpeg 1600w"></a></div>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"> </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Rule number two: trade on secure devices.</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">There are some things in this world called malware, or simply viruses, malicious code. When your phone or computer is infected. It can copy your entire keystroke or copy-paste cache. Therefore, when trading on an account with a large amount of money. Make sure your device is completely secure. What is safety equipment?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">1. Phone is brand new or has been reset to factory settings, only install the official banking application for transactions. In addition, do not use to access any web or install any other software. This phone is for transfer only. Run out of. After using it, disconnect the 4G and Wifi network.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">2. Your own computer, do not use public computers or other people's computers. Do not install pirated, hacked, or unlicensed Winddows because they are already pre-installed with malicious code. Also only install trusted web browser apps downloaded from the homepage like chrome, edge, firefox. Do not install any other software or browse the web, facebook etc. This machine is only used for money transfer. End.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">If you only have one computer, try using the live Linux operating system installed on a usb stick. When you need to use it to transfer, plug it in. After using, turn off the device, remove the USB and store it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">3. All your banking devices and applications must have strong passwords. Above 8 characters, use special characters. Do not use passwords that contain information related to you personally such as: date of birth, wife and children, wedding date, ID number, favorite color, etc. Because they are easy to guess if your device falls into the hands of crooks.</span></p>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjj9lfeDSZ-XnrSDltl2bkaXkt0Tk59zD0BamZJVRNVy_PfMZyYdfFk-CtuSX19ontQBSxjoRWB0spWUbZ5cLXOLdp9Ay3veOKIEgv-kwYpBRwjq3HhuvXI-rNeaW2eslPKUjfxsdVSL6HvepnGnzM2Qo834_e7ttrYaINYHo3RFCmOXf4x9Rcb0u7W/s1920/pexels-media-2882630-1682703984057.jpeg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/pexels-media-2882630-1682703984057.jpeg" width="640" height="426" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-2882630-1682703984057-xs.jpeg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-2882630-1682703984057-sm.jpeg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-2882630-1682703984057-md.jpeg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-2882630-1682703984057-lg.jpeg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-2882630-1682703984057-xl.jpeg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-2882630-1682703984057-2xl.jpeg 1600w"></a></div>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"> </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Rule number three: connect securely.</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Once the device is secure, the connection you use must also be secure. The 4G connection of the telecom operator is relatively safe, because the packets are encrypted with a high level of security. It is difficult for crooks to decipher packets transmitted over 4G.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Wifi connection has the following requirements:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Must use your own wifi. This wifi only shares passwords with trusted devices in the house. Absolutely do not use public wifi or home wifi that has shared the password with too many people. Because wifi system can intercept packets easily if hackers share wifi with you. The hacker will then decrypt your packet to get user name and password information.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">If using OTP sms, make sure this phone number is only used for banking transactions, not public, not normal calls. This will reduce the risk of fraudsters knowing the phone number. Fraudsters will fake, scam to forward messages, calls from your number to their number. More advanced, they can perform a high-tech attack to trick the telecommunications carrier's transceiver system to capture the packet containing your OTP sms.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Sincere advice is: the sms protocol is old and weakly encrypted. It will be better if you switch to Smart OTP over the internet. They are generated right on the device. Connecting to the bank's encrypted server is much more secure than sms.</span></p>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhQQvqlLjc5T3CunXr58vppUtPp9Tpev-cHXYD9e2OP2_imQcWmsgqe4RqQEicU1N4r3eMlbQk-4D0B4rkhge6aw_S3eFBCyOpPa37K9dZfqAoAQLgC7-WmgNzkkk2cdvxY0Ky-zfY8KlDkag-4g_tMvz-dNyWfHSptB_ieZpESkHAobmwCqmtz4tQl/s1920/pexels-media-1602726-1682709293929.jpeg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/pexels-media-1602726-1682709293929.jpeg" width="640" height="426" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-1602726-1682709293929-xs.jpeg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-1602726-1682709293929-sm.jpeg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-1602726-1682709293929-md.jpeg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-1602726-1682709293929-lg.jpeg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-1602726-1682709293929-xl.jpeg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/43/responsive/pexels-media-1602726-1682709293929-2xl.jpeg 1600w"></a></div>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Money is debt and banking is a joke</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tipeas</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://tipeas.com/money-is-debt-and-banking-is-a-joke.html"/>
        <id>http://tipeas.com/money-is-debt-and-banking-is-a-joke.html</id>
        <media:content url="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/48/pexels-karolina-grabowska-4386476-2.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="USA"/>
            <category term="Treasury Bonds"/>
            <category term="Taxes"/>
            <category term="Money"/>
            <category term="FED"/>
            <category term="Economy"/>
            <category term="Debt"/>

        <updated>2023-05-07T11:10:00+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/48/pexels-karolina-grabowska-4386476-2.jpg" alt="" />
                    "The problem with fiat money is that it rewards the minority who can handle the money, but misleads the generation that has worked and saved money." - Adam Smith, the first economist. The father of capitalism. Have you ever wondered: How more money is printed?&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/48/pexels-karolina-grabowska-4386476-2.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"> </span></p>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgv0WVwHM-L5R96MGRhgMb1AcCLRbjO3rQ1nfnzepOE_g_G35KNr-P7TU5C6OG1IgEKZE3TgRfjmVTtAkN6aZTjRq-WuWzEscVI9SwXIGSnEz9NA5iTJGKQ1BPhL9Junjwxg_BR_ixB7N0y16tv4QUk6XqjPiIfaQID7BtXvg9QAO9uUG5kYc9_E5NQ/s6253/pexels-karolina-grabowska-4386476.jpg" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/48/pexels-karolina-grabowska-4386476.jpg" width="266" height="400" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/48/responsive/pexels-karolina-grabowska-4386476-xs.jpg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/48/responsive/pexels-karolina-grabowska-4386476-sm.jpg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/48/responsive/pexels-karolina-grabowska-4386476-md.jpg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/48/responsive/pexels-karolina-grabowska-4386476-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/48/responsive/pexels-karolina-grabowska-4386476-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/48/responsive/pexels-karolina-grabowska-4386476-2xl.jpg 1600w"></span></a></div>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"><i>"The problem with fiat money is that it rewards the minority who can handle the money, but misleads the generation that has worked and saved money."</i> - Adam Smith, the first economist. The father of capitalism.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Have you ever wondered: How more money is printed? I wondered the same thing when I was sitting in the lecture hall.People like to print as much as they want.  Or how money became valuable when it was invented.  It also circulates through different countries.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Until I found the book: James Rickards' Currency Wars, a true science book. Don't confuse it with Song Hong Bing's "Currency War". From this book, recently, tiktok and facebook emerged many financial experts with conspiracy theories about jewish oligarchs. In fact, it is no different from a fictional story with subjective imposition, disguised as a research work.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">James Rickards is an economist who designs economic war scenarios and tests them for the US Department of Defense and the Pentagon. He even came up with a scenario that recently came true: Russia and China joined hands to kick the dollar out of international payments.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">In a nutshell, he explained about printing and issuing more money as follows:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Previously when there was still a gold standard. A country's money is backed by gold in the national treasury. When you want to issue more money, you must also have the same amount of gold in your inventory. This ensures that the monetary circulation mechanism and inflation and deflation indicators are automatically adjusted.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Today, when the whole world has abandoned the gold standard. One way for governments and central banks to issue more money is for new money to be backed by bonds. And a bond is a debt, that's right, friend, it's a debenture, nothing more. It is promised by the government to repay the debt, with taxes that the government collects later.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">That is, the central bank is borrowing the tax money of the future to consume for the present. Ridiculous. They print new money, and tell people: they guarantee it the value of a note, for an unknown amount of money in the future.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">It is really very very reliable.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Once there are bonds, the central bank offers them for sale. Partially recovered in local currency and foreign currency (foreign debt). Newly printed money will be brought out through attractive interest rate loan packages or stimulus packages, rescue, debt redemption, companies. In the first stage, the market will absorb all this new money. If there is inflation. It will be regulated by: The central bank will sell foreign currency, or continue to offer bonds, or stocks that they own to collect local currency.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">In essence, money is now debt.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Mr.Baker has 10$ deposited in the bank.  The bank keeps 1 dong, the remaining 9$ is lent. You borrowed that 9$ from the bank to buy Flower's land. Ms.Flower took 9$ and deposited it in the bank.  The bank owes Mr.Baker and Ms.Flower 1$ of deposit interest. But you owe the bank 2$ of loan interest. Lend more times that amount.  The more debt the bank has, the more interest it will earn. From only the initial 10$, through countless loans, debts are continuously created with interest. This is the money created out of nowhere.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">At this point, someone will object: that interest will be taken from another bank.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">But people just think about it. There is no limit to the number of times a bank can lend a loan. The money in circulation is limited. So the amount of interest generated is infinite from the debt.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">The more banks involved in this scenario, the more complicated the path of money becomes, giving people the illusion that it just flows from one bank to another.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Money is now more than paper, it's just numbers on the screen, with confidence in the government and the future.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">What happens when people rush to withdraw money in banks? What happens when the government has too much debt to pay? The economy collapsed. Because it was built on a castle with an air foundation. There is no actual asset corresponding to that amount, both paper and virtual. The more we borrow from the bank, the poorer we become by it. And the future that we think is secure thanks to the money we have in the bank, in the safe at home, is uncertain. The future of the economy, the future of people, especially the underdeveloped countries, has never been as fragile and fragile as it is now. Because underdeveloped countries will be forced to borrow their money by the IMF, World Bank and other financial institutions to get out of the economic crisis.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">The global economy, the global supply chain means that we are no longer autonomous. From what we eat, to the medicine we drink and the air we breathe, is all governed by money. And the currency can be dominated by foreign individuals and organizations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"><i>"All money is a matter of trust."</i> - Adam Smith</span></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Why will the US remain the number one power?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tipeas</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://tipeas.com/why-will-the-us-remain-the-number-one-power.html"/>
        <id>http://tipeas.com/why-will-the-us-remain-the-number-one-power.html</id>
        <media:content url="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/50/pexels-pixabay-290386-2.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="USA"/>
            <category term="The Rise"/>
            <category term="Economy"/>
            <category term="Capitalism"/>

        <updated>2023-05-07T10:48:00+07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/50/pexels-pixabay-290386-2.jpg" alt="" />
                     ‘Every individual is continually exerting himself to find out the most advantageous employment for whatever capital he can command. It is his own advantage, indeed, and not that of the society which he has in view. But the study of his own advantage naturally, or&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/50/pexels-pixabay-290386-2.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"> ‘<i>Every individual is continually exerting himself to find out the most advantageous employment for whatever capital he can command. It is his own advantage, indeed, and not that of the society which he has in view. But the study of his own advantage naturally, or rather necessarily, leads him to prefer that employment which is most advantageous to society… He intends only his own gain, and he is in this, as in many other cases, led by an invisible hand to promote an end which was not part of his intention</i>’  - Adam Smith, founder of capitalism.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: times; font-size: medium;">America has always been and will always follow this ideology radically.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"> </span></p>
<table class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" align="center">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjFKaC-ch39hiqFwCe-4ztfaXx0DYLCjwzSkyv9ahfLW4h59Fs6BaOu8v1l2vejlwWJN-J1ZMixMW9baBu3Qtn95bJgKCxhDZHEy0ICIHaF2iZbIj9F_YzLyfzxuTJ8vh59pv3gnlJOtCQs63PFW1B9uhk_w9WMeccL075KBI8mHbS00pNBJbtcUBVH/s6912/pexels-pixabay-290386.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"><img loading="lazy" src="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/50/pexels-pixabay-290386.jpg" width="640" height="386" border="0" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="http://tipeas.com/media/posts/50/responsive/pexels-pixabay-290386-xs.jpg 300w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/50/responsive/pexels-pixabay-290386-sm.jpg 480w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/50/responsive/pexels-pixabay-290386-md.jpg 768w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/50/responsive/pexels-pixabay-290386-lg.jpg 1024w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/50/responsive/pexels-pixabay-290386-xl.jpg 1360w ,http://tipeas.com/media/posts/50/responsive/pexels-pixabay-290386-2xl.jpg 1600w"></span></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;">Ambition is facilitated by freedom. And that propels America to the top.<br></span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"> </span></p>
<div><span style="font-family: times; font-size: medium;">Review the history of countries. Is there any country that is not ambitious. But America has always been the most ambitious country. Leading in professions and fields, world hegemony in military and economy. But which country has both great ambition and the government creates the maximum conditions for its citizens to do business and develop? Only America.</span></div>
<div><span style="font-family: times; font-size: medium;">Ambition on the one hand, it can destroy a person when he just indulges in it. But on the other hand, it's the driving force that drives him up and up. Like war, it must be there to promote the development of society. It's war in any way. From military to economy, culture.</span></div>
<div><span style="font-family: times; font-size: medium;">One country has risen dramatically recently: Israel, with its rapid development. Going from nothing to an economic, high-tech and even military powerhouse. The US and Israel have much in common. Like the US, Israel is also a country of immigration. But mainly ethnic Jews. Jewish immigrants always have a strong desire to develop and start a business. America is different, America is a multi-ethnic and religious immigrant country. This gives the United States a much larger and more diverse internal strength. On the other hand, Israel's motivation is to develop to protect the homeland and the country. But America's driving force is the ambition to lead and hegemony. Different goals, different results.</span></div>
<div><span style="font-family: times; font-size: medium;">Is Switzerland free? It is impossible to claim that they are 100% free if freedom is demanded in the true sense of the word. But Switzerland is one of the few countries with a direct democracy. The majority of the people can reject the laws enacted by the state. But why is Switzerland not the leading power? Because Switzerland has never been ambitious.</span></div>
<div><span style="font-family: times; font-size: medium;">Does China have ambitions? Very ambitious. But they also have never been free to develop, do business, and are not really protected in terms of personal property.</span></div>
<div><span style="font-family: times; font-size: medium;">America has always been ambitious and also does a pretty good job of its liberal ideology. In the context that the world is moving from a unipolar US-led order to a multipolar one. America will always be in its number one position. Because while other countries are still developing industrial production, self-sufficient in technology and currency. Then the US still went before holding a lot of cards. Much of the intellectual property in the most sophisticated semiconductors remains in the United States. The best artificial intelligence companies, the largest data warehouse are also in America. Quantum computer technology is also leading US companies. The key technologies of the future are in their hands. The problem is not how strong the dollar is in the world, nor where oil and gas will be extracted, who will be sold, or what payment will be made. The problem is that the world will still be very dependent on American products, and will still have to do a lot of business with the US. Simply because they hold an important resource: ambitious individuals free to pursue their own interests.</span></div>
<div><span style="color: #374151;"><span style="font-family: times; font-size: medium;"> </span></span></div>
<div><span style="font-family: times; font-size: medium;">So what about less developed countries? The issue they need to focus on is not how their domestic currency compares to other foreign currencies. Will the USD lose its dominance, or where will Bitcoin fit into the international reserve and payment system? History has proven, in all currency wars, short-term benefits don't always rescue from long-term recession and unemployment. As a small nation, its currency value is low compared to the currencies of wealthier countries. To be proactive, learn from Israel. Learn and master essential skills and technologies. There's no need to lead, but figure out how to turn it into a strength. Use that as an inherent strength to create genuinely valuable products. When they do that, they will persist no matter how the global stage shifts.</span></div>
<div> </div>
<div><span style="font-family: Crimson Text; font-size: medium;"><i>‘I have never known much good done by those who affected to trade for the public good.’ </i>- Adam Smith</span></div>
<div> </div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
